When I'm working with a new library,
当我接触一个新的库的时候
I like to try it out in the interactive shell.
我喜欢先在交互式 shell 中间尝试一下
This is the fastest way to try out its methods in syntax.
这是熟悉这个库的方法和语法最有效的方式
I have opened the Beautiful Soup Documentation besides
在我的 terminal旁边 我打开了 BeautifulSoup 的文档
my terminal so I can reference it as I try it out.
以便在我尝试例子的时候来作参考
The documentation has its convenient quick start guide that we can follow along with.
文档有一个简单方便的快速起步指导 我们可以跟着来做
Let's start at the Python interpreter and import Beautiful Soup.
先来打开一个 Python 编译器 然后导入 BeautifulSoup
The documentation suggests we import the library with this line
文档提示我们这样导入此库
here from bs4 import BeautifulSoup.
"here from bs4 import BeautifulSoup"
Next, the documentation shows how to create a soup object from a string.
接下来 文档展示了如何从字符串创建一个 soup 对象
The quick start guide uses a small html sample that's in a string.
快速起步指导使用了一个短小的 html 字符串来展示
I've always thought though that I learn best when I don't follow some instructions
我认为当我自己并不严格遵循所有指示的时候 我能学到更多
exactly so I think I'll make a soup object out of a Wikipedia's html source instead.
所以我决定用 Wikipedia 的 html 来创建一个 soup 对象
Charlie showed us how to get an html string with requests so we'll do that here.
Charlie 已经向我们展示了如何用 requests 拿到一个 html 字符串 我也在这里照着做
I'll get Wikipedia's main page and store it source in a variable called html.
我先得到 Wikipedia 主页的 html 文档 然后在叫 html 的变量里面存储它
Let's verify that we got the html.
我们先确认我们得到了 html 源码
Whoa, that's a lot of html.
哇 这是很大篇幅的 html 源码
Now, let's make it into a soup object using these instructions from the documentation.
现在 让我们根据文档的提示 用它来创建一个 soup 对象
The quick start guide suggests that we get the title tag like this.
快速起步指导建议我们这样来取得一个 html 中的 tag
Okay, that works.
嗯 是可以做到的
Good. Let's try getting a paragraph tag.
好的 我们先来获取一个 &lt;p&gt; 标签
The documentation says we can do that with soup.p.
文档上说我们可以用 soup.p
OK. This is a lot of html again,
可以 我们再次获得了一堆 html 源码
but at least it's just one paragraph.
好在篇幅只是一个段落
I'll open Wikipedia in my browser to compare this to what the browser displays.
我要在我的浏览器打开 Wikipedia 以便对比获得的源码和浏览器展示的内容
It looks like today's featured articles about Frost's bolete,
这些内容看上去是今日特色条目关于 Frost's bolete 的内容
a type of fungus, and that's the same paragraph we got from Beautiful Soup. Great.
它是一种真菌 并且正是我们 BeautifulSoup 里面的内容 真棒
If you want the first instance of a paragraph tag on a page, we use soup.p.
如果你想要页面里面第一个段落的代码 我们使用 soup.p
We can get nested tags like this, soup.p.a.
我们还可以得到嵌套在内的 tag 比如 soup.p.a
This selects the first anchor tag inside of the first paragraph tag.
这样我们选择了第一个 &lt;p&gt; 标签中的第一个 &lt;a&gt; 标签
In this case, it's a link to the featured article.
这时 它指的是特色条目
The rest of this quick start guide shows how to get
快速起步指导剩下的部分展示了
lists of anchor tags instead of just one tag.
如何以列表的形式获得标签而不仅仅是获得一个标签
Install Beautiful Soup, open up the documentation in the terminal,
现在轮到你安装 BeautifulSoup 打开官方文档
and try this out for yourself.
然后自己试试看